ERIC SHIELDS

SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER

CONTACT

resume@ericrshields.com

linkedin.com/in/ericrshields/

Seattle, WA

SKILLS

JavaScript (ES6)

React.js

TypeScript

Git

HTML5 & CSS3

Jest

jQuery

Java

SQL & Databases

Spring

RESTful APIs

SOFTWARE

Linux Google Docs Windows MS Office Basic graphic design Intellij Slack Project Management

EDUCATION

Rochester Institute of Technology

B.S. in Computer Engineering

2001 - 2007

Community Service Head for the House of General Science

PROFILE

Senior Frontend Engineer with 15 years of General Web Development experience on legacy and modern frameworks. Dedicated to Sustainability, Waste reduction, and Ethics/Equity. Perpetual mentor and mentee.

Turning designs into **beautiful**, **simple**, **functional**, and **accessible** web interfaces with a mind for **scalability**, **reuse**, **testing**, and **performance**. Prioritizing the highest standards in code, communication, documentation, and **integrity**.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CLIMATEBASE FELLOW

2023

Climatebase Fellowship - Cohort 3

Remote

 Participating in the Climatebase Fellowship, a climate career accelerator for mission-driven professionals

FRONT END ENGINEER II

2019 - 2022

Amazon Web Services - Service Catalog Console

Seattle, WA

- Assisted migration of the SC console from AngularJS 2.x to React, Redux, TypeScript, NPM, ESLint, Webpack, & Babel
 - Complete rewrite of the console from scratch—old console code was able to be 100% deprecated and deleted!
 - Upgraded JS unit test to Enzyme, jest, and React Testing Library
 - Managed a complex transition period with both apps active
- Led launch of the console in the 2nd US Government special region
 - Updated the region launch process, reducing the time to launch a new region by over 50%
 - Built the foundation for a future launch in China
 - Built project template; Recognized by senior leadership as a desirable example for the whole organization to follow
- Engineering and project lead for analytics research and integration
- Completed the complex migration of the core OS on 150+ web servers, including dev boxes, alpha, beta, and production
- Created extensive documentation of projects and team processes, such as code and CR guidelines, project templates, and guides
- Performed extensive and in-depth code reviews, earning the title of "team code gatekeeper"; especially during the early migration
- Co-founded the team's Cultural Lunch & Learn program, a regular meeting to discuss sensitive issues like equity, sustainability, or politics in a safe and inclusive environment
- Mentored several team members, who became high-impact devs

CONTACT

resume@ericrshields.com

linkedin.com/in/ericrshields/

Seattle, WA

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Agile Methodologies

Kanban

Cross-functional Collaboration

Communication & Teamwork

Problem Solving

Continuous Integration / Continuous Deployment

Software Documentation

RECOMMENDATIONS

66Eric gives new meaning to one of Amazon's primary leadership principles: "insist [on] the highest standards"."

JUSTIN, AWS

Eric is one of the best people I've worked with at AWS, he is very diligent and sets a very good example for others to leave the campsite cleaner than before. His code and technical design are very thorough, and he gives great feedback and suggestions. 99

VARUN, AWS

Eric's passion for sustainability and equity was clearly inspiring not just for me but also for the team. Any team would be lucky to have Eric, and I couldn't recommend him more for any business looking for new talent.9

TAUSEEF, AWS

View more recommendations at linkedin.com/in/ericrshields/details/recommen

WORK EXPERIENCE (CONT.)

WEB DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER II (DESIGN TECHNOLOGIST)

Amazon.com - Search Design Technology

Seattle, WA

2017 - 2019

· Extensively collaborated with designers, engineers, and managers for both the Information architecture and the feature set

- As a solo dev, delivered an entire custom prototype website of 20+ pages of markdown content across several distinct designs within 45 days and it presented to senior org leadership (phase 1)
- For phase 2, built all (internal) customer-facing UI and the macro system for use in the CMS editor
- For phase 3, provided supporting functions similar to PM, engineer, designer, TPM, and content architect. Provided "daytime on-call" support across the entire stack

WEB DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER II (SDE)

2015 - 2017

Amazon.com - Retail Search Customer Experience

Seattle, WA

- Altered display of B2B items based on customer's and item's properties
 - Maintained a complex logic tree of display possibilities
 - Improved 100,000+ items to provide contextually relevant information and call-to-action
- Led development for Comparison View, which surfaces the top product specs for items directly in the search results
 - Wrote code encompassing the full stack, including datapath (custom database), Java, JSP, JavaScript, and HTML/CSS
 - Collaborated extensively with the catalog, recommendations, and hardlines teams, along with product and QA
 - o Increased OPS by a confidential, statistically significant amount

FRONT END DEVELOPER; CLIENT ENGINEER; CUT UP ARTIST

2009 - 2015

Synacor - Various Teams

Buffalo, NY

- Created and maintained complex JavaScript applications
 - Wrote close to 75% of the JS and 95% of the HTML/CSS for Primetime 2.0, a ground-up re-write of the video channel
 - Replaced two 4000-line JS files with a proper framework of small
- Worked with client managers to handle client requests and product deployments
- Worked on internal projects to improve portal deployment speed and accuracy
 - o Reduced the average time-to-launch for small ISPs from 2 weeks to 2 hours
- Converted designs into HTML & CSS, pixel perfect in IE6-9, Safari, FireFox, and Chrome

Application Developer Associate Professional

2006 - 2008

BAE Systems - Information Technology

Binghamton, NY

 Created custom data-driven websites for internal clients using Oracle APEX, JavaScript, SQL, and PL/SQL